

MOHAMED AHMED BAHAIDAR (Ph.D.)

EDUCATIONIST, BUSINESS & MARKETING CONSULTANT, SOCIOLOGIST & AUTHOR.

Contact:

Email: drbahaidar@gmail.com Cell: +254740049095/+254777772271 Languages: English, Kiswahili and Arabic.

Intellectual Competence:

Extensive research of 14 years has seen me go through over 2,000 books in matters concerning Philosophy, Psychology, Leadership, Entrepreneurship, Mediation, Theology, Business modules, Social issues and also dealt with more than 10,000 cases of solving business predicament, personal issues and family conflicts. My managerial skills, coupled with my knowledge of social and business affairs, make me a valuable resource for counseling tips.

Education:

Doctorate Degree: **Doctor of Philosophy in Management** Thesis Tittle: "Successes and setbacks in management system practices"

Thesis Supervisor: Prof. Gopala Mariappan Krishna

Date Earned: Jan 2014 to June 2016

University: University of New Castle (AIMS)

Kuala Lumpur - Malaysia

Master's Degree: **Master in Business Administration**Thesis Tittle: The reason behind business failures.

Date Earned: Feb 2012 to Nov 2013

University: University of New Castle (AIMS)

Kuala Lumpur - Malaysia

Bachelor's Degree: Bachelor in Business Administration

Date Earned: Feb 2009 to Nov 2011

University: University of New Castle (AIMS)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Publications:

The Hidden Self - The Vitiating Elements and Impending Barriers to Achieving What We Desire. (Published The First Edition in India 2012 And A Revised Edition in The UK In 2018.)

The Point of Deflection - The Discrepancy between Our

Experience:

Job Title: Business Proprietor

Company: Doctor Bahaidar Consultancy Ltd and CEO OF IQRA

FM Nairobi - Kenya.

Dates From 15th May 2020 - To date.

 DR. BAHAIDAR CONSULTANCY LTD - We provide case studies and practical solutions to assist sole proprietors and enterprises streamline operations and achieve thresholds of success.

How do we do it?

 We incorporate our knowledge and experience in identifying bottlenecks and pursuing viable business practices. Dr. Bahaidar offers a unique and personalized approach to problem solving and achievement of goals and objectives.

How long is the Consultancy?

 The onboard process takes three to six months to achieve the intended results.

Referrals

- *A number of businesses have been assisted through our intervention. These include:
- * Restoration of the Green Garden Restaurant Zanzibar.
- * Establishment of a management system for Ala Noor Restaurant in Zanzibar.
- * Creation of enticing marketing strategies, clearing debts, and resolving management issues at IQRA FM as the CEO.

Job Title: Acting Manager

Company: **Alshaya (Debenhams)** Mall of Qatar (Doha - Qatar.)

Dates From 30th July 2016 - May 2020

- In charge of cosmetics department.
- Training & developing staff abilities.
- · Overseeing stocks controller's work
- Initiating business growth.

Job Title: Manager

Company: Savoy Real Estate & Gelato Divino

Mombasa - Kenya

Expectations and Actual Results. (Published In the USA In 2018.) A Household of Bliss – The Disturbing Query Which Perturbed Many. (Published In the USA In 2019 - Process Ongoing). Mirror Reflection - The urge to quit the race manifests itself. (Published In the USA In 2021 - Process Ongoing). Sparkling Hope - The more the derisory individuals are in chaos, the easier it becomes to maneuver through codes of threat and disaster. (Published In the USA In 2021 - Process Ongoing).

Written Biography:

The Abandon Testimony of Abdul Gani - A Lance of Betrayal Embedded in a Bleeding Heart.

Ongoing Publications:

- **1. The Anonymous Trek -** An invigorating concept for us to be able to forge forth.
- 2. My Dash of Existence The causes our enervation.
- Millionaire's Quest We are just one idea away to be a millionaire.
- **4. Trailing the Scent of Sex -** The perception of pleasure.
- The Living Silhouette A humble orphan (The comforter).

Award:

Having worked on a number of projects that provided pragmatic solutions to social and business-related matters has enabled me to be the recipient of the most distinguished award in Middle East, North Africa, and Asia, the Meena Personal Brand Award, which was awarded in Muscat, Oman, in 2019.

Achievements:

A few of the public speaking invitations I received were from Stamford International University - Bangkok - Thailand, City University - Kuala Lumpur - Malaysia, a 3-day seminar at Kenya Institute of Foreign Languages and Professional Studies in Nairobi - Kenya, and Zanzibar - Tanzania. I had speaking engagements included Sumait University, Melisha College, and many more. Furthermore, I regularly appear in a number of East African media outlets and they publish articles about me frequently.

References:

 Prof. Gopala Mariappan (Asian Institute of Management Science)

Email: profdrgopala@gmail.com

Cell: +60133699531

Kuala Lumpur - Malaysia.

2. Ghazi Aldakheel (Debenhams Area Manager)

Email: ghazi@alshaya.com
Cell: +96598851192

Kuwait.

Dates From May 2012 - To April 2016

- In charge of all departments and stores.
- Create company awareness through marketing
- Training and reviving inner motive.
- Rent, purchasing & selling of houses.
- Interviewing, short listing & recruiting.
- Allocating job descriptions.

Job Title: Lecturer

Company: PLATINUM school of business management

Mombasa - Kenya

Dates From Jan 2012 - To March 2016

Evening classes

- Lecturing business courses (Marketing, Management, and Business communication, Business English, Business Math, Consumer Behavior, Organizational Behavior, Human Resources Management, Entrepreneurship, Ethics and Social Responsibility, Sales Management.)
- Guiding and counseling students.
- Training and reviving inner motives
- Soft Enrichment Skills.

Job Title: Sales and Marketing

Company: BNG holding Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur - Malaysia

Dates From Nov 2009 - To sept 2011

- Client negotiation & selling strategies
- · Sales consultant
- Uplifting sales and customer follow up.

Media path:

Having worked as a media personality and content producer for 10 years as a part-time job. All along public speaking has been my passion for serving society through counseling at a wider range and at the same time producing content which will be impactful by tackling our East Africa social issues and educating.

I have attached a link to a documentary we produced 10 years ago. https://youtu.be/Nsh57gUICX4

Discussion as sociologist in Citizen

https://youtu.be/KJHzqSHZgwg

And our currently East Africa Talk show (The Doctor M Bahaidar Show)

https://mega.nz/file/SNZjEYyD#2m1B-

Kxs037Va3tdnxit56cEcpsfGx4zl5pNEy8YcRc

We do our own series which we just started

https://youtu.be/RaxGrQ28nbc

Cheka Na Doctor B

https://voutu.be/v2b2eAfdAoM